Melissa Hazlewood

linkedin.com/in/melissahazlewood | melissahazlewood.github.io

Summary

Persistent problem-solver and hard-working optimist; a machine learning engineer instrumental in taking a safety-critical medical device from the research stage to design verification (DV) and successful pre-market approval (PMA) for investigational device exemption (IDE); software engineer with 2+ years experience focusing on deep learning, image segmentation, object detection, machine learning model analysis, and the model pipeline.

Technical Skills

Languages Libraries Operating Systems Python, C, C++, Java

NumPy, Pandas, TensorFlow, SciPy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, ROS, Pytest Linux, Mac OS X, Windows, Ubuntu, Pop! OS

Experience

Software Engineer, Bionaut Labs

October 2022 - Present

- Owned the model pipeline of a convolutional neural network (CNN), particularly using a simplified UNet architecture, used for the computer vision task central to the Bionaut robotic surgery system.
- Improved the model's accuracy in predicting the two key features by 95 and 92%, while decreasing the training time by 80%, by pivoting strategies for training the CNN model.
- Achieved a 77% reduction in model prediction errors by improving the training datasets, leading to its successful use as the final model release for design verification and the approved IDE submission.
- Successfully demonstrated the Magnetic Propulsion System to investors, leading to millions in funding.
- Designed and built a PyTest plugin for automated testing, allowing faster design verification.
- Conducted a large migration of experiment data to Azure Cloud Storage, reducing storage costs by 98%.
- Optimized high-speed camera to achieve filming rates up to 500 fps, an 8x improvement, by reverse-engineering configuration files and developing custom Python API scripts.
- Implemented new GitHub Actions workflows for automated testing and continuous integration/continuous deployment (CI/CD); debugged and optimized old workflows, saving hundreds of dollars in overage fees and data transfer costs.

Computer Lab Technician, California State Summer School for the Arts

July 2022 - August 2022

- Served nearly 300 artists as the program's first ever technology support specialist, finding solutions to any software or hardware problem, developing a ticketing system, and configuring all lab computers.
- Increased automation in all aspects of the job; for example, Python scripting reduced one of the data entry tasks from multiple days to just minutes.

Education

Computer Science, M.S. Physics, B.A. and Astrophysics, B.A. California State University, Long Beach (CSULB) University of California, Berkeley (UCB)

Projects

Facial Recognition using Pre-trained Networks

March 2021 - April 2021

- Used YOLOFace model to detect faces in a given picture and place a bounding box around each one.
- Applied FaceNet model to cropped faces, outputting an embedding vector representation whose distance when compared to other images' embedding vectors measures the similarity in the constituent faces.

LEGv8 - Processor Simulation in Verilog

August 2020 - December 2020

- Modeled a processor with a simplified ARM instruction set architecture able to load, store, add, subtract, pass (through the datapath with no action), and apply logical operations to data.
- Incorporated pipeline registers between processing stages (IF, ID, EX, MEM, and WB) to increase throughput.